# **Tyler Adkins**

Email: adkinsty@icloud.com Website: adkinsty.github.io Phone: (517) 927 3467 Address: Ann Arbor, MI

### Summary

PhD candidate in cognitive neuroscience with 6+ years of experience conducting quantitative research on human behavior. Actively seeking positions in data science and user research so I can apply my domain knowledge and technical skills to the development of cutting-edge technologies.

### Skills

Python (pandas, numpy, sklearn), R (ggplot, dplyr, brms, rstan), Stan, Git, Bash, SQL, experimental design, data cleaning, data visualization, inferential statistics, machine learning, cloud computing, quantitative reasoning, scientific writing, public speaking, teaching, mentoring, problem-solving

## **Employment**

9/2017 – Present Graduate Student Researcher University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI Cleaned and visualized complex datasets, programmed computational models of behavioral data and machine learning models of brain images, collaborated with diverse teams of scientists on many research projects, reported research findings in reputable journals and conferences, mentored colleagues in data analysis.

1/2018 – 4/2020 Graduate Student Instructor University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI Created educational materials and assessments for instructors and students in large lecture courses, provided instruction and tutoring to students in multiple discussion sections, graded written assignments and quizzes

9/2015 – 9/2017 Research Assistant University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI Configured eye-tracking hardware and software, implemented econometric models of movement planning.

#### **Education**

9/2017 – Present	Ph.D. in Psychology (CCN)	University of Michigan	Ann Arbor, MI
1/2015 – 9/2017	B.A. in Cog. Sci. & Philosophy	University of Michigan	Ann Arbor, MI

#### Awards

2021	Swets Memorial Award for Psych. (\$25k)
2019	NSF GRFP (honorable mention)
2018	Scholarship in Math. Psych. (\$3k)
2017	Rackham Merit Fellowship (\$100k)
2016	Phi Kappa Phi
2015	Sweeney Merit Scholarship (\$3k)

#### Service

2021	Departmental Associate
2020	CCN Forum Committee
2020	CCN Admissions Committee
2019	CCN Social Committee
2018	Recruitment Committee

### **Projects**

Adkins and Lee (2021) Neuroimage [DOI]
Adkins, Lewis, and Lee (2021) Psych. Bulletin & Review [DOI]
Adkins, Gary, and Lee (2021) Nature Scientific Reports [DOI]
Anderson, Adkins, and Lee (2020) J. Neurophysiology [DOI]
Fansher, <b>Adkins</b> , and Shah (in press) <i>JEP</i> : Applied
Adkins and Lee (in review) Psych. Bulletin & Review [DOI]
Fansher, <b>Adkins</b> *, et al. (in review) <i>Memory and Cognit</i> . [DOI]
Fansher, Adkins*, et al. (in review) Cognit. Research: P&I [DOI]
Brissenden, <b>Adkins</b> , et al. (in review) <i>JEP: General</i> [DOI]
Lalwani,, <b>Adkins</b> ,et al. (in review) <i>Psych. Science</i> [DOI]
Adkins, Zhang, Jonides, and Lee (in prep)
Adkins, Weissman, and Lee (in prep)

<sup>\*</sup>Shared first authorship